flaviar.com 2019-05-10

# Privacy Policy

**Protecting Your Privacy**

When you use Flaviar's Website or Mobile App, you are providing some personal information about who you are and how you use our services. We collect, store and analyse this information to deliver your orders, monitor technical performance of our services, discover the bugs and offer better services for the next visitors.

At Flaviar we are committed to protecting the security of your personal information we collect and protect your privacy. This document describes more in detail, what information we collect, how we store it and share it with third parties, and what we do with that information. Please, read on if you want to learn more.

**Who We Are**

The Company behind flaviar.com is Flaviar, Inc. with headquarters in New York, NY. The Company acts as Data Controller for all our services. You can reach us by sending email to [hello@flaviar.com](mailto:hello@flaviar.com?Subject:Privacy%20Policy).

**How This Policy Applies**

To perform our services and communicate with you, we need to collect some information about you. This Policy describes what information we collect, how we use that information and the legal basis for doing so. It also explains, how collected information may be used and your rights regarding information you provide to us.

**What Information We Collect and Receive**

When you use our Website, App or communicate with us regarding our services, we may collect personal information from you.

_Visiting flaviar.com or using Flaviar Mobile App_

We record information how you use and interact with our Website and Mobile App, such as your IP Address, type of device or browser you use.  

_Engaging in Speakeasy Club_

If you decide to apply for joining Flaviar Speakeasy Club, we collect your email address and phone number that allows us to communicate with you regarding the Club and other offers from Flaviar.

When you join the club, we also collect your billing information such as your name, email, billing and shipping address and credit card details.

To tailor our services for you, we collect your interests on specific drinks and drink types, your ratings of specific drinks and your reviews of specific drinks.

_Shopping on flaviar.com_

If you shop on flaviar.com, we collect your billing and shipping information such as your name, email, billing and shipping address and credit card details.

We maintain a record of products you have ordered to be able to fulfil the orders. We keep the record of all your orders for accounting purposes.

We also maintain a record of products that are out of stock, but you expressed interest in using “+ Add to Wishlist” feature that allows us to inform you when the product is back in stock.

If you submit any personal information relating to other people to our service providers or to us, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**How We Use this Information**

We need this information to:

  * Learn about how you use our Website and Mobile App and decide about changes, we want to implement to make your experience better,
  * Communicate with you as Speakeasy Club Member to communicate about benefits you have as a member,
  * Communicate with you regarding our latest offers,
  * Process your orders to deliver fine spirits you ordered on our Website or through our Mobile App.

**What is the legal background for us to collect this Information**

We collect and retain Personal Information on several legal bases:

  * Contractual obligation: if you gave us your personal information in connection with the order you placed with us, we need this information to deliver the Goods or Services to you.
  * Legal obligation: in some cases, it is required by the law to collect and store your Personal Information. For example, tax laws require that we keep all the sales records and, in some cases, share it with local tax authorities.
  * Legitimate interest: for some data, we have good and fair reason to use it in such ways that do not hurt your interests and rights. Example of that would be that we use your information like location, browser information, IP address, billing and shipping address, email address, to prevent fraud and abuse of our Services.
  * Consent: when you deliberately enter your information, like your email address or rate a product on our Website or in Mobile App, you should expect that this information will be stored and used by our systems according to this Privacy Policy.

**How long do we keep this Information**

Your information will be stored as long as your account is active to provide you with the Services you expect from us.

Some of your personal information, like your shipping and billing addresses, will be stored with our partners or us as long as required by different laws that we need to comply with (for example tax laws).

We also collect and maintain aggregated, anonymised or pseudonymized information which we may retain indefinitely to protect the safety and security of our Site, improve our Services or comply with legal obligations.

You can always request deletion of your Personal Information by sending a request to [privacy@flaviar.com](mailto:privacy@flaviar.com?Subject:Privacy%20Policy).

**How do we share this Information with our partners**

We don’t publish any information about our users publicly.

If you choose to review products on our Website or in Mobile App, we will add your First Name (as set in your Profile) together with the review.

We share some information with our trusted third-party services that help us provide, improve, promote or protect our Services (Data Processors). Those third-party services include payment processors, fulfilment partners, services that help us manage our adds and similar. Third-party services are authorised to use your personal information only in connection with services they provide for Flaviar, and we require to use the same security and privacy standards as we do. When possible, we anonymise and aggregate the information we share with third-party services so that they are not able to identify you as an individual.

**How can you manage your Privacy settings**

You can always see, update and delete your Personal information we store from your Account Settings page.  

_SMS Settings_

If you are receiving SMS from Flaviar and would like to unsubscribe you can respond to any messages received with STOP and you will no longer receive our messages.

We may retain specific information as required by law or as necessary for our legitimate business purposes.

Because Flaviar, Inc. is a US-based company, your information will be collected and processed in the United States. The United States has its own laws governing data protection and government access to information. The rules that protect your personal information under United States law may be different than in your home country. If you choose to use the Services, you need to agree to our Terms of Use, which set out the contract between Flaviar and its users.

We understand that security of your personal information is especially important. We protect the collected data according to the industry-standard practices and continuously improve security protocols. However, we understand that no electronic storage of the data or transmission over the internet is entirely secure and we can not guarantee absolute security. Therefore we encourage all users to be careful whenever they store or post any personal information online.

If you have any concerns or questions about how your data is being used or stored or any information that is related to security of your or other user’s data on Flaviar, please reach out to our Data Protection Officer by sending email to [privacy@flaviar.com](mailto:privacy@flaviar.com?Subject:Privacy%20Policy).

**Changes to how we Protect Your Privacy**

We may update this Policy from time to time, to reflect how we are processing your data.

If we make significant changes, we will make that clear on this page and let you know about it, so you will be able to review the changes before you continue to use our services.
